在下一段，大约三十只小海龟里，我们会处理 L 的另一个方面，
In our next paragraph, about 30 little turtles, we deal with another aspect of L,
也就是辅音丛。当你遇到 D-L 组合时，需要应用什么？
namely consonant clusters. When you have a D-L combination, you need to apply what
你已经学过连读、美式 T，以及 L。
you learned about liaisons and the American T as well as the L. Since the two
两个声音在口腔中的位置相近，所以你知道它们会
sounds are located in a similar position in the mouth, you know that they're going
连在一起，对吧？你也知道这些中间位置的 T 都会
to be connected, right? You also know that all of these middle T's are going to be
先发 D，然后把舌头留在上腭位置。
pronounced D, and that you're going to leave the tongue stuck to the top of your
这可能会让你疑惑：空气从哪里出去？
mouth. That may leave you wondering, where is the air to escape? The L sound is what
这由 L 音决定。发 D 时，要把气流憋住，就像词尾 D 一样。
determines that. For the D, you hold the air in, the same as for a final D. Then
发 L 时，气流从舌头两侧释放出来。
for the L, you release it around the sides of the tongue. Let's go through the steps
然后再进入下一项练习。
before proceeding to our next exercise.